# **TANMAY KALE**

#### Fremont, CA

(607) 297-0376 | tanmay.kalee@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Software Engineer / Application Developer with 2+ years' experience in Web and Software development alongside academic experience in Data structures, Algorithms, Mobile/Web development and Database techniques. Excellent communication skills, team player and a healthy appetite for learning new technologies quickly. Looking for an opportunity that would challenge me to grow professionally and help me cultivate my passion for computer science even further.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Science
State University of New York, Binghamton (SUNY Binghamton)

**Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology** 

University of Mumbai, India

May 2017

3.3 / 4.0

June 2014

68.00%

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, C, C++, JavaScript, HTML5, Python
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, Oracle 10g/11g, MS SQL Server, IBM DB2, MongoDB
- Frameworks: Spark, ReactJS, React Native, Ruby on Rails, Spring 3, Hibernate, JQuery
- Tools and IDEs: Eclipse, Net beans, Intellij, Atom, Microsoft Office, MongoDB Compass, Xcode, Maven, Ant
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Object Oriented Design/Programming, Refactoring, Design Patterns, MVC

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer | Patience & Fortitude | Los Angeles, CA

Nov 2017 - Present

- Collaborated closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions by implementing high-quality,
   high-performance mobile application using React Native in JavaScript
- Extended app features by implementing **GoogleMapSDK** to point the posted house on GoogleMaps and retrieve neighborhood information by using Google Place API along with FacebookSDK to create accounts and log into the app
- Contributed in debugging, support, and release of the app to the app store
- Used Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL to build data storage solutions for storing and retrieving data.

# Software Developer Intern | Binghamton University | Binghamton, NY

July 2017 - Oct 2017

- Involved in the creation of sample UI for standalone course registration system benefiting 1200 registered students involving registration for 33 courses using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery for frontend and MongoDB at the backend
- Developed an algorithm to smartly manipulate and analyze assignment of courses for 1200 students in a non-biased method thus simplifying professor's course registration work by 20% efficiently
- Performed A/B testing for website optimization and improve performance of the application

## Software Developer Intern | Thinkstrap Technologies | Mumbai, IN

May 2016 – August 2016

- Designed and developed automated health check RESTful web service in Java (Jersey / JAX-RS) to track status of 6+ online
  systems to determine system's total availability percentage at any given instance
- Developed the application with **Agile** methodology using **Spring MVC** architecture and **Hibernate** to map the Java classes along with MySQL server database and **ANT** to build the application
- Carried out Test Driven Development using mock objects to emulate system's behavior for real-time scenario
- Interacted with team lead and team members for design improvements and wrote readable & reusable code using Design Patterns along with extensive use of **GIT** for version control

# Web Developer | Innovations | Nashik, IN

January 2014 – June 2015

- Gathered, analyzed and documented business requirements. Elicited functional specifications for development team.
- Collaborated with team to develop website and devise solutions for clients' technical problems.
- Developed E-Commerce websites, integrated payment gateways providing end-to-end e-commerce solution.
   Technologies used: WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Google Analytics, AdWords, Social Media Ads

# **PROJECTS**

#### Design Patterns | Java

- Developed an algorithm using multithreading for Object Pool API using Singleton and Factory Pattern for allocating 4 courses to 100 students based on 7 different preferences while keeping the average preference score minimal
- Built a well-designed application for reading the statistics of a given file using Visitor pattern in Java
- Implemented a backup system using **Observer** pattern to notify and update backup records when file is modified
- Built an application to read different class details from a file, creating and populating objects of the respective classes accordingly using java reflection API. Parallely keeping track of number of unique and duplicate objects created
- Used ANT for building and deploying the application along with GIT for version control

https://tkale1.github.io/ github.com/tkale1/ linkedin.com/in/tanmaykale

# iOS Application Development | Objective C, Swift, SpriteKit, Firebase Framework, Git

- Designed and developed 9 iOS games individually and with a group of 2 to 4 members for all Apple devices
- Developed Guess the Song Music Quiz! A multiplayer iOS game application to compete over 100+ songs
- Implemented Phrase Based Machine Translation(PBMT) model using **Google Cloud Translation API** to develop an **iOS** application supporting languages translation for 207 languages conforming to ISO-679-1 Code

# **Data Mining for Trend Predication** | Java, Design Patterns

- Developed a **Java** application for implementing item based collaborative filtering for analyzing consumption pattern for 15000+ users and 1400+ items.
- Implemented logger to report and persist error and warning messages for future analysis

### Database Technologies | Java, JavaScript, JSP, HTML/CSS, JDBC, PL/SQL

- Developed a GUI based Retail Business Management System with a team of 3 using Oracle's **PL/SQL** with interactive menudriven UI in HTML/CSS for handling inventory of 15 items in the store
- Programmed stored procedures, sequences, user defined functions, database triggers and packages and all the database objects needed for relational database with 6 tables

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (pursuing)
- MongoDB for Java Developer (2017)
- IBM's Rational Application Developer (RAD) and DB2 (2012)